https://matmccabe.github.io/MMcCabe.github.io/

Mathew McCabe

Technical writer with a skill set extending into a variety of areas within communications and technical writing. I have had the privilege of working within social media, academics, health communication, technology, end user, marketing, public affairs, and HVAC systems. I am excited to share my experiences and continue my growth as a writer and communications specialist.

EDUCATION

State University of New York at Oswego — Master of Arts Strategic Communications

- Analyzed, researched and produced social scientific information relevant to business and academics.
- Guest lecturing and teaching undergraduate communication materials.
- Succeeded in big business, small business, academic, and nonprofit communication.
- Worked with computer mediated communication software with basic front-end development, database structuring and human computer interaction.

State University of New York at Oswego — Integrated Media and Social Networks Certificate of Advanced Study

- Performed network research and analysis to stay independent and successful in the expanding social media and tech based communication field.
- Computer Science Usability and Technical Documentation.
- Developed and maintained front-end websites with html, css, and wordpress.
- Produced and managed multimedia communication for small and nonprofit businesses.

State University of New York at Oswego — B.A. Public Relations

- Developed strong writing and interpersonal communication skills.
- Worked thoroughly in business and nonprofit organizational settings.
- Promoted teamwork and fast paced assignments with deadline focused work.

EXPERIENCE

Consolidated Claims Group — Technical Writer

Feb. 2019- Current 40 Hours per week.

- Create end user reports of HVAC system damages including current pricing, damage analysis, technical explanation, and insurance recommendation.
- Collaborate in person and remotely using company communication software such as Salesforce and Google Drive technology.
- Provide professional customer service and technical recommendations to insurance adjusters who have requested consultation in their claims resolution process.
- Provide technical support to field technicians using the organization's integrated mobile and web applications.
- Industry Leading knowledge and implementation of HVAC and refrigeration practice.

United States Small Business Administration Office of Disaster Assistance, Travel — *Public Affairs Specialist*

November 2018- January 2019 40-50 Hours per week.

- Public speaking, assisting in preparing and disseminating media kits, and oral communications to target and key audience members.
- Built contacts and schedules for media and information events.
- Constructed and maintained progress and financial logs while working remotely.
- Executed grassroots campaign to provide relief information to disaster survivors.

Oswego Lifestyles Center, Oswego NY — Social Media Health Promotions

August 2017- May 2018 20 hours per week

• Researched, edited and distributed weekly health publications to target audiences.

- Ran and developed a blog, social media, and website to support campaign efforts.
- Managed and utilized current media technologies such as Hootsuite and Adobe suite.
- Developed relationships with a variety of campus organizations to collaborate on information, recruitment, and advertising.
- Mentored and graded two student committees in the production/editorial process.

DAS Labs, American Fork UT — Brand Ambassador

April 2018- Present 2 hours per week

- Promoting health and wellness via social media by posting.
- Regularly using social media to market and distribute DAS products.
- Engage current and potential social media audience with sales and updates.

Zink Shirts, Oswego NY — Marketing Intern

September 2015 - May 2016 15 hours per week

- Create a multi-media campaign to digitally engage the audience including press releases and social media campaigns.
- Plan campaigns by identifying goals, business requirements and outreach benchmarks.
- Engaged community through public relations events.

Wordpress Open Source Contributor — Volunteer Contributor

August 2020 - Current

- Work as part of a multinational team to maintain and develop documentation for Wordpress.
- Develop, edit and contribute to the end-user documentation for the wordpress web application.
- Develop, edit, contribute and test code as part of the wordpress code documentation team.
- Utilize common industry tools such as Slack, Google Drive and Wordpress.

Additional Skills and Certificates

- +JAVA and Python Languages
- +REST API Technical Documentation
- +CRUD Technical Documentation
- +XML, HTML, JSON Technical Documentation Languages
- +Technical Manual Documentation
- +WordPress Development
- +Adobe Suite Software

Affiliations and General Interests

- +Zeta Beta Tau Fraternity +Classical Music +Automotive Mechanics
- +Golf +Health & Fitness +Community Service +HVAC +Computer Science
- +Word Press Open Source Contributor